Tero Ankkuri

CONTACT

+358 40 7658 775 teroankkuri@gmail.com teroank.dev GitHub/tetaankk LinkedIn





ABOUT ME

Creative problem solver with a business background who decided to utilise their Excel enthusiasm properly and go for coding. Programmed the first time at 12 years old, always done IT as a hobby and took courses at the Uni, but only this year decided to do it seriously and make a career out of it.

In personal projects I've used **React (JS & TS)**, **Node**, **MongoDB and MySQL** as well as **Git**. In (past) study projects I've gotten some familiarity with **C#** and **Python**. Very capable of quickly adopting new concepts and all things IT. Take a glance at my portfolio site or <u>GitHub</u> to see where I'm at!



EXPERIENCE

Analyst

UseLess Company 10/2020 - 5/2021

- Calculating carbon footprints for SM enterprises
- Building reusable and accurate Excel templates for handling large data masses in multiple use cases, bringing substantial efficiency improvements
- Proposing emission reduction pathways
- General start-up business development

Trainee & Associate

PwC Finland 8/2019 - 2/2020

- Carrying out data analyses and migration testing using data analysis software and Excel to support risk management
- Auditing IT-systems
- Development of CSR reporting

Finance Assistant

Arvato Financial Solutions 7/2017 - 9/2017

• Evaluating and financing of clients' sales invoices while managing risk

Customer Delight Specialist

Finnchat 1/2017 - 8/2017

• Supporting B2B and B2C customers on various websites through a chat service



EDUCATION

University of Jyväskylä

M.Sc. (Econ & B.A.) 2018 - 2021

- Major: Corporate Environmental Management
- Minor: Environmental studies
- Master's <u>thesis</u> on the climate impacts of small knowledge companies

B.Sc. (Econ & B.A.) 2015 - 2018

- Major: Information System Science
- Minor: Accounting
- Bachelor's <u>thesis</u> on blockchain tehnology and different consensus mechanisms

Management Center Innsbruck

Student exchange in Innsbruck, Austria 2017 - 2018

• Studies in Business & Management module



LANGUAGES

Finnish first language

English fluent

Swedish sufficient

German basics



HOBBIES

- Crossfit
- Reading, broadening of mind and imagination
- Movies (dystopic movies especially)